Guide to the Edgar Odell Lovett and Mary Ellen Hale Lovett Family papers, 1849-1979 MS 494
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Edgar Odell Lovett and Mary Ellen Hale Lovett Family papers
1849-1979
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Lovett, Edgar Odell, 1871-1957
MS 494
43.25 Linear Feet (87 boxes)
Family correspondence, photographs, travel and community involvement records, business information, newsclippings, academic realia and genealogies for the Edgar Odell Lovett family and related families such as the Hale and Wicks families. In addition to providing detailed family history, this material documents the close administrative and philanthropic relationship of the Lovetts and others primarily to Rice Institute, and to a lesser degree the Art League of Houston and the Houston Museum of Fine Arts.
87 boxes
Biographical Note
LOVETT, EDGAR ODELL (1871-1957). Edgar Odell Lovett, mathematics professor and president of Rice Institute (now Rice University), was born in Shreve, Ohio, on April 14, 1871, the son of Zephania and Maria Elizabeth (Spreng) Lovett. After graduating from Shreve High School he entered Bethany College, Bethany, West Virginia, where he graduated in 1890 at the age of nineteen. From 1890 until 1892 he was professor of mathematics at West Kentucky College; in 1892 he became an instructor at the University of Virginia, where he continued his studies and received the degrees of M.A. and Ph.D. in 1895. The following year he studied in Europe at the universities of Christiana and Leipzig; he received M.A. and Ph.D. degrees from the latter in 1896. In 1897 Lovett lectured at Johns Hopkins University and the universities of Virginia and Chicago. In September of that year he became instructor in mathematics at Princeton University. He was promoted to assistant professor of mathematics in 1898 and from 1900 to 1905 held the rank of professor. From 1905 to 1908 he was both professor and head of the Department of Mathematics and Astronomy at Princeton.
In 1907 he was asked to head Rice Institute, then being planned at Houston; he was recommended for the post by Woodrow Wilson, then president of Princeton. He accepted in 1908, moved to Houston, and was formally inaugurated as the first president of the institute on October 12, 1912; he continued in this capacity until his retirement on March 1, 1946. Thereafter, he was associated with Rice as president emeritus, director, and consultant.
He was a member of many learned societies, including Phi Beta Kappa, the London Mathematical Society, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, the Circolo Matematico di Palermo, Société Mathématique de France, and the Royal Astronomical Society. The degree of LL.D. was conferred on him by Drake University, Tulane University, Baylor University, and Bethany; that of Sc.D. was conferred upon him by Colorado College. In 1898 Lovett married Mary Ellen Hale of Mayfield, Kentucky; they had two daughters and two sons. He died on August 13, 1957, and was buried in Glenwood Cemetery, Houston.
BIBLIOGRAPHY: Sam Hanna Acheson, Herbert P. Gambrell, Mary Carter Toomey, and Alex M. Acheson, Jr., Texian Who's Who, Vol. 1 (Dallas: Texian, 1937). American Philosophical Society Yearbook, 1956-57. Houston Chronicle, August 14, 1957. Houston Post, August 14, 1957. Houston Press, August 14, 1957. New York Times, August 14, 1957. Proceedings of the Philosophical Society of Texas, 1942, 1957. Clay Bailey
"LOVETT, EDGAR ODELL." The Handbook of Texas Online. <http://www.tsha.utexas.edu/handbook/online/articles/view/LL/flo34.html> [Accessed Thu Sep 30 11:30:31 US/Central 2004 ].
Scope and Content
Family correspondence, photographs, travel and community involvement records, business information, newsclippings, academic realia and genealogies for the Edgar Odell Lovett family and related families such as the Hale and Wicks families. In addition to providing detailed family history, this material documents the close administrative and philanthropic relationship of the Lovetts and others primarily to Rice Institute, and to a lesser degree the Art League of Houston and the Houston Museum of Fine Arts.
Extensive family correspondence and photographs form over half of the collection. Three boxes of postcards, photographs, guidebooks and more related to the World Tour (1908-1909) taken by E.O. and Mary Lovett to gather ideas for the formation of Rice Institute are also of particular interest.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Eliza Lovett Randall donated the papers on behalf of the Lovett/Baker family in 2002.
Arrangement
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence, 1849-1979 (Boxes 1-22)
Series II: Photographs, 1859-1954 (Boxes 23-37)
Series III: World Tour, 1908-1909 (Boxes 38-40)
Series IV: Printed materials, 1885-1973 (Boxes 41-46)
Series V: Community Involvement and Financial records, 1890-1951 (Boxes 47-52)
Series VI: Personal materials and realia, 1907-1977 (Boxes 53-63)
Series VII: Addendum, 1865-1951 (Boxes 67-86)
Related Material
Rice University President's Office records: Edgar Odell Lovett.
Edgar Odell Lovett personal papers, MS 60
Index Terms
Subjects
Education; Universities and colleges
Document Types
photographs; genealogies (histories)
Subjects (Persons)
Baker, Walter Browne, Jr., 1925-1994; Lovett, Adelaide; Hale, Henry S., Major; Hale, Henry S., Jr.; Hale, Anne B.; Lovett, Alexander; Lovett, Guy; Lovett, H. Malcolm (Henry Malcolm), 1902-1997; Lovett, Maria Elisabeth Spreng; Lovett, Martha Wicks; Lovett, Mary Ellen Hale
Subjects (Corporations)
Art League (Houston, Tex.).; Museum of Fine Arts, Houston.; Rice University.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1849-1979, 219467
  - Edgar Odell Lovett to Mary Hale Lovett, 219576
    - June-August, 1906, 219597 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - September - December, 1906, 219596 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - January-March 19, 1907, 219595 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - March 20 - July, 1907, 219594 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1908, 219593 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - January - June, 1909, 219592 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - July-August, 1909, 219591 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - September - December, 1909, 219590 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - January - July, 1910, 219589 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - August, 1910, 219588 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - September-December, 1910, 219587 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - January - June, 1911, 219586 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - July - December, 1911, 219585 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - January - October, 1912, 219584 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1913, 219583 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1914, 219582 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1915, 219581 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1916, 219580 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 1917, 219579 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 1918, 219578 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 1919-1937, 219577 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Mary Hale Lovett to Edgar Odell Lovett, 219559
    - July 1909 - June 1911, 219575 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - July - September, 1911, 219574 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - October 1911 - September 1912, 219573 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - October 1912 - October 1913, 219572 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - November 1913 - August 1914, 219571 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - September 1914 - July 1915, 219570 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - August 1915 - September 1916, 219569 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - October 1916 - July 1918, 219568 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - August 1918 - October 1919, 219567 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - November 1919 - September 1921, 219566 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - October 1921 - February 1922, 219565 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - March 1922 - December 1924, 219564 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - January 1925 - May 1927, 219563 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - June - October, 1927, 219562 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - November 1927 - April 1943, 219561 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - no date, 219560 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Malcolm Lovett - Edgar Odell Lovett, 1907-1920, 219554
    - 1907-1920, 219558 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1921, 219557 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 1922-1923, 219556 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1924-1957, 219555 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Adelaide Lovett - Edgar Odell Lovett, 219551
    - 1906-1912, 219553 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1903-1929, 219552 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Alexander Lovett - Edgar Odell Lovett, 219546
    - 1914 - July 1931, 219550 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - August 1931 - October 1933, 219549 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - November 1933 - 1935, 219548 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1936-1955, n.d., 219547 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Malcolm Lovett - Mary Hale Lovett, 219542
    - 1908 - August 1921, 219545 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - September 1921 - 1939, and n.d., 219544 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Postcards to Malcolm Lovett, 1906-1910, 219543 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Adelaide Lovett - Mary Hale Lovett, 1906-1947, and n.d., 219541 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Alexander Lovett - Mary Hale Lovett, 1913-1948, 219540 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Adelaide Lovett - Malcolm Lovett, 1914-1927, 1961, 219539 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Mary Hale Lovett - Children, 1903-1913, 219538 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Adelaide and Browne Baker - Edgar Odell Lovett, 1927-1935, 219537 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Misc. to Adelaide Lovett Baker, 1931-1939, 1954 and n.d., 219536 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Lovett children, 1906-1929, 1957 and n.d., 219535 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Lovett family members, 1947-1977, 219534 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Maria Elisabeth Spreng Lovett (mother of EOL) - Edgar Odell Lovett, 1913-1934, 219533 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Maria Elisabeth Spreng Lovett (mother of EOL) - Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1907-1935, 219532 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Guy and Gertrude Lovett (brother of EOL) - Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1907-1926, 219531 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Guy and Gertrude Lovett (brother of EOL) - Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1929-1934, 219530 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Guy and Gertrude Lovett (brother of EOL) - Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1935-1943, and n.d., 219529 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Lovett family to Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1907-1956, 219528 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - William Lindsay and Bess Hale to Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1912-1953, 219527 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Nathan Hale - Mary Hale Lovett, 1919-1929, 219526 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Mr. & Mrs. J.T. Hale - Mary Hale Lovett, 1911, 1949, n.d., 219525 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Henry S. Hale to Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1911-1915, 219524 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Henry S. Hale to Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1916-1931, 1940 and n.d., 219523 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 80th birthday celebration for Major H. S. Hale, May 4, 1916, 219522 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Planning for 80th birthday celebration for Major H. S. Hale, May 4, 1916, 219521 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Misc. to Major Henry S. Hale, 1916-1919, and n.d., 219520 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Major Henry S. Hale to Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1905-1913, 219519 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Major Henry S. Hale to Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1914-1920, 219518 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Adelaide Hale - Mary Hale Lovett, 1901-1916, 1932, 219517 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Anne B. Hale - Edgar Odell Lovett and family, 1895-1913, 219516 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Hale family, 1897-1898, 1911, 219515 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Gregory family and Hale family, 1849-1877, 1930 and n.d., 219514 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Hale family to Lovett family, 1906-1919, 219513 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Hale family to Lovett family, 1920-1949, 219512 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Misc. to Hale family, n.d., 219511 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Malcolm Lovett - Martha Wicks, January - September, 1928, 219510 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Malcolm Lovett - Martha Wicks, October - December, 1928, 1936, 219509 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Misc. to Malcolm and Martha Lovett, 1964-1979, 219508 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Wicks family - Business, 1931-1951, 219507 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Wicks family, 1858-1953, 219506 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Wicks family, 1954-1967, n.d. (includes genealogies and Martha Wicks memorabilia, 219505 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Edgar Odell Lovett letters of introduction, 1908-1910, 219504 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Edgar Odell Lovett, Princeton, 219499
    - 1890-1906, 219503 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1895, 1900-1906, 219502 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1907, 219501 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1908-1909, 219500 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Edgar Odell Lovett - Rice, 1907-1908, 219498 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - President's house plans at Rice, 1911, 219497 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Misc. to Edgar Odell Lovett, 219490
    - 1877-1910, 219496 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - 1911-1915, 219495 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - 1916-1936, 219494 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - January - August, 1937, 219493 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - September 1937 - 1957, 1977, 219492 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - n.d., 219491 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Misc. to Mary Hale Lovett, 219480
    - 1906-1910, 219489 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 1911-July 1913, 219488 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - [Carrington Weems to Mary Hale Lovett, 1908-1911], 219487 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - August 1913-1915, 219486 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 1916-1917, 219485 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - 1918-1929, 219484 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Paris trip, 1921-1922, 219483 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - 1930-1948, 219482 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - n.d., 219481 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Misc. invitations, 219475
    - 1906-1915, 219479 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - 1916, 219478 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - 1917-1919, 219477 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - 1920-1952, n.d., 219476 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Garden party, June 1929, 219474 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Supper party responses, party on June 4, 1939, 219473 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Rice commencement garden party responses, party on June 5, 1939, all responses May-June, 1939, 219472 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Rice commencement garden party responses, party on June 5, 1939, all responses n.d., 219471 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Edgar Odell Lovett death (died August 13, 1957), August 13-15, 1957, 219470 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Edgar Odell Lovett death (died August 13, 1957), August 16 - December, 1957, 219469 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Misc. correspondence, 1929, 1952, 219468 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Series II: Photographs, 1859-1954, 219392
  - Edgar Odell Lovett, 1898, 1908, 1954, and n.d., 219466 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Edgar Odell Lovett, all photographs undated, 219465 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Mary Hale Lovett, 1890s-1920s, and n.d., 219464 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Adelaide, Malcolm, and Alexander Lovett, ca. 1910- and n.d., 219463 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Malcolm Lovett, 1910s, 1921, and n.d., 219462 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Lovett relatives, all photographs undated, 219461 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Browne Baker, Jr., ca. 1930 and n.d., 219460 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Adelaide Lovett, ca. 1921 and n.d., 219459 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Martha Wicks Lovett, all photographs undated, 219458 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Mary Elisabeth Spreng Lovett, ca. 1916, 219457 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Ellen Kennedy Lovett, ca. 1906 and n.d., 219456 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Photographs from France, ca. 1921, 219455 (Box 26, Folder -)
  - Misc. Lovett family, 1926-1928, and n.d., 219454 (Box 27, Folder -)
  - Framed images of Major H. S. Hale and Virginia Adelaide Hale, 1859, 219453 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Mary Hale Lovett and Virginia Adelaide Hale, n.d., 219452 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Major H.S. Hale and sons, ca. 1913, 219451 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Major H.S. Hale, ca. 1890 and n.d., 219450 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Major H.S. Hale, ca. 1860-1915, n.d. and n.d., 219449 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Adelaide Hale, ca. 1865-1912, n.d., 219448 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Hale family, 1860s-1910s, n.d., 219447 (Box 29, Folder -)
  - Hale family gravesite, Hale family homestead, and Martha Wicks, 1890s-1920s, 219446 (Box 30, Folder -)
  - Edgar Odell Lovett college friends, Ohio friends, observatory friends, 1880s-1900s, 219445 (Box 31, Folder -)
  - Friends of Hale family in Kentucky, ca. 1880s-1920s, n.d., 219444 (Box 32, Folder -)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, 219443 (Box 33, Folder -)
  - Rice Institute photographs, all undated, 219434
    - Lovett Hall, 219442 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Commencements, 219441 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Construction, 219440 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Garden parties, 219439 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Pershing Day, 219438 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - "The Sisters" fountain, 219437 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors, 219436 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 219435 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Oversize photographs, 219393
    - Framed photo of Jacob Lovett and wife, n.d. (ca. 1850s?), 219433 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Albert Sydney Hale (brother of Mary Hale Lovett), n.d., 219432 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Martha Wicks Lovett, n.d. (ca. 1960s?), 219431 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - 25 photos of Martha Wicks Lovett, n.d. (ca. 1920s?), 219430 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Major H.S. Hale (4 photos), n.d., 219429 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified persons (3 photos), n.d., 219428 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Malcolm Lovett (20 photos), 1928-1950s, 219427 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Malcolm and Martha Lovett (4 photos), ca. 1950s, 219426 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Boards of Directors, including Malcolm Lovett (5 photos), 1960s-1970s, 219425 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Eliza Lovett, 1937, 219424 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Martha Lovett (5 photos), ca. 1930s, 219423 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Martha Wicks (Lovett) (2 photos), n.d., 219422 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Marjory Hasselmann, 1936, 219421 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified, n.d., 219420 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified child (granddaughter of E.O. Lovett?), n.d., 219419 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Helen Wicks Link (3 photos), n.d., 219418 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Malcolm and Martha Lovett, ca. 1950s, 219417 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Sketch of unknown, n.d., 219416 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Eliza Lovett wedding photos, May 4, 1952, 219415 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Edwin Robert Wicks (7 photos), n.d., 219414 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified wedding photos (5), n.d., 219413 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified child ( photos), n.d., 219412 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Browne Baker Jr. (4 photos), ca. 1930s, 219411 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Silhouette of unknown child, n.d., 219410 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified, n.d., 219409 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Unidentified woman (5 photos), n.d., 219408 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified women, n.d., 219407 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Camp Dixie for Boys, n.d., 219406 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Newsclippings and 2 photographs of Frances Hale, 1937, 219405 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Lovett Baker, 1937, 219404 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Browne Baker Jr., 1937, 219403 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Colleagues and mentors [?] of Edgar Odell Lovett, n.d., 219402 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified persons, n.d., 219401 (Box 37, Folder 6-8)
    - Henry S. Hale Jr., n.d., 219400 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Woodrow Wilson memorabilia, n.d., 219399 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Alexander Lovett, 1922, 219398 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Mary Hale Lovett (9 photos), n.d., 219397 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Mary Hale Lovett with children (3 photos), n.d., 219396 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified child, n.d., 219395 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Lovett granddaughters (3 photos), n.d., 219394 (Box 37, Folder 15)
- Series III: World Tour, 1908-1909, 219379
  - Postcards grouped by location in alphabetical order, Athens-Zurich; oversize enlargements of ship postcard in box 37, 219391 (Box 38, Folder -)
  - Numbered negatives from Lovett World Tour with descriptive listing, 219390 (Box 39-39a)
  - Mixed negatives and prints, 219389 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Munich photographs, 219388 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Paris photographs, 219387 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Zurich photographs, 219386 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Mixed European photographs, 219385 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous photographs collected on world tour, 219384 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Business cards, lists of cities visited, questions asked, Professor possibilities, 219383 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Artist's proofs for Stanford University buildings, 219382 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Transportation schedules and maps, 219381 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Guidebooks and printed materials, 219380 (Box 40, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Printed materials, 1885-1973, 219334
  - Oversize diplomas and tributes, 219340
    - Edgar Odell Lovett, 219363
      - Honorary doctorate, Tulane University, March 22, 1911, 219378 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - High School, Shreve, Ohio, 1885, 219377 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Bachelor of Arts, Bethany College, 1890, 219376 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Honorary Master of Arts, Bethany College, 1894, 219375 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Ph.D. and M.A. University of Virginia (also contains seven graduate certificates), June 12, 1895, 219374 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Honorary doctorate, Baylor University, June 16, 1920, 219373 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Honorary doctorate, Princeton University, June 16, 1946, 219372 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Honoring first president of Rice, Nov. 7, 1941, 219371 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - 25th anniversary of first Rice Institute commencement, June 7, 1941, 219370 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - Society of the Sigma Xi, March 23, 1938, 219369 (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - Announcement of Lecture by Foreign Educational Mission, Fall 1918, 219368 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Announcement in honor of British Educational Mission, Fall 1918, 219367 (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - Honoring retirement from Rice (2 copies), May 23, 1941, 219366 (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - Diploma of thanks for service to Rice, May 12, 1946, 219365 (Box 41, Folder 14)
      - French Legion d'Honneur, April 15, 1938, 219364 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Mary Hale Lovett, diploma from West Kentucky College, 1892, 219362 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - H. Malcolm Lovett and Martha Lovett, 219355
      - Service to Rice University, July 13, 1973, 219361 (Box 41, Folder 17)
      - Friends of Fondren, October 16, 1982, 219360 (Box 41, Folder 18)
      - Diploma from Rice Institute, June 6, 1921, 219359 (Box 41, Folder 19)
      - Friends of Fondren Library Award, October 16, 1982, 219358 (Box 41, Folder 20)
      - Completion of Catholic Confirmation, March 20, 1921, 219357 (Box 41, Folder 21)
      - Certificate from Kinkaid School, June 2, 1921, 219356 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Major H. S. Hale, 219347
      - Confederate monument (2 copies), n.d., 219354 (Box 41, Folder 23)
      - Certificate of marriage, November 8, 1865, 219353 (Box 41, Folder 24)
      - Election as Treasurer of Kentucky, August 3, 1891, 219352 (Box 41, Folder 25)
      - Confederate Veteran Association of Kentucky, April 29, 1892, 219351 (Box 41, Folder 26)
      - American Christian Missionary Society, July 10, 1901, 219350 (Box 41, Folder 27)
      - Election as Treasurer of Kentucky, August 31, 1891, 219349 (Box 41, Folder 28)
      - Addie Gregory: Diploma from Female Institute, July 6, 1859, 219348 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - Mrs. H.S. Hale: Christian Woman's Board of Missions, July 20, 1909, 219346 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Mrs. V.A. Hale: Daughters of the Confederacy, n.d., 219345 (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - Anne B. Hale: Induction into Daughters of the Confederacy, n.d., 219344 (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - Anne B. Hale: Diploma from Occidental College of Kentucky, June 7, 1887, 219343 (Box 41, Folder 33)
    - Edwin and Helen Wicks: marriage certificate, December 12, 1899, 219342 (Box 41, Folder 34)
    - Certificate given to "Truth Seekers Bible Class," July 29, 1910, 219341 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Oversize 19th century scrapbook, program and materials from Formal Opening of Rice Institute including official program belonging to E.O. Lovett., 219339 (Box 42, Folder -)
  - Rolled items: Malcolm Lovett house plans, Lovett family memorial at Glenwood Cemetery, 1969 Rice University landscape plan, 219338 (Box 43, Folder -)
  - Books, 219337 (Box 44, Folder -)